<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teis Lindemark</title>
    <description>My name is Teis Lindemark and I am a software developer, beer home brewer and an Agent backer. Disclaimer: The opinions expressed on this blog are my own personal and do not represent my employer&#39;s view in any way. 
</description>
    <link>http://www.teilin.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.teilin.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 22:26:00 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 22:26:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Howto Install Jekyll and Octopress 3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; a while back, but for some reason I stoped using it. It was because I thought the &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; blog engine would be what I always wanted. Then I started reading about Octopress 3 and some collegeas at work told me how good that one is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the biggest upside for me choosing Octopress is because it is a static site. Which means that I can use my Github account to host the blog for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started looking around to see if anyone had a nice walkthrough how to setup Octopress 3 and I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chrisanthropic.com/blog/2014/installing-octopress-3-0-from-scratch/&quot;&gt;chrisanthropic.com: Installing Octopress 3.0 From Scratch&lt;/a&gt;. That looked like what I was looking for. After a while, it was clear to me that this guild was a little bit outdated, so here are the steps I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;install-octopress&quot;&gt;Install Octopress&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install octopress
gem install bundler
octopress new &amp;lt;yourblogname&amp;gt;
cd &amp;lt;yourblogname&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;create-a-git-repository&quot;&gt;Create a git repository&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a repository at Github where you want to publish your blog. Then you need to add some lines to your .gitignore file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;_deploy.yml
.bundle
bin
vendor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;build-your-blog&quot;&gt;Build your blog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The part I used some time to find out was how I was suppose to build the blog. Everywhere I looked different blogs included the guide I followed had the command &lt;code&gt;octopress build&lt;/code&gt;. By looking at the subcommand to octopress, there are no build command. Then it got to me that it probably is Jekyl that should be used to build the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll build
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;deploy-your-blog&quot;&gt;Deploy your blog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;octopress deploy init &amp;lt;git@github.com:teilin/teilin.github.io.git&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;octopress deploy init&lt;/code&gt; command, the _deploy.yml file is generated. I did not do any changes in this file at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running &lt;code&gt;octopress deploy&lt;/code&gt; now, will deploy your site to your Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 20:57:56 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.teilin.net/2015/07/13/howto-install-jeckyll-and-octopress-3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.teilin.net/2015/07/13/howto-install-jeckyll-and-octopress-3.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
